usac.org 2019-02-22

# Website & Privacy Policies - USAC.org

Updated May 2018

Thank you for visiting the Universal Service Administrative Company (USAC) website. USAC is the independent, not-for-profit corporation that administers the federal Universal Service Fund (USF) and the four universal service programs under the oversight of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC). Below is information on USAC's Privacy Notice, Rights under the Privacy Act of 1974, and USACs Website Policy.

#### Skip to:

  * USAC Privacy Notice
  * Rights under the Privacy Act
  * USAC Website Policy

#### USAC Privacy Notice

This Privacy Notice describes the practices of USAC (USAC, we, or us) with respect to personal information we collect through our website. USAC is committed to protecting the privacy and security of its visitors to this website and of any personal information that we collect during your visit. Except as described below, USAC does not collect personal information from or about you when you visit our website. USAC may update this Privacy Notice from time to time and without notice. If the Privacy Notice is updated, the last modified date of the policies is reflected in the upper right hand corner of this page.

By "personal information", we mean information that can be used to identify you and also information that, when combined with other information from or about you, can be used to identify you. Examples of personal information include your name, physical address, email address, telephone number, social security number and other government identifiers, unique identifiers for the devices you use to access this website, and user identification (ID) and password for any accounts you create with USAC. USAC may also collect personal information through the FCC forms that are used to administer the Universal Service Fund (USF) and the universal service programs, or through questions submitted through USAC's website.

Except for the automated collection activities described below, website visitors do NOT have to provide information when searching, retrieving, downloading, or otherwise accessing and using the USAC website.

If you have questions about this Privacy Notice or about our collection and handling of your personal information, please contact USAC's Director of Privacy at [privacy@usac.org](mailto:privacy@usac.org).

Show All

#### Rights Under The Privacy Act Of 1974 

The Privacy Act of 1974 (Privacy Act) (5 U.S.C. § 552a) prohibits the disclosure of information about individuals that the federal government maintains in a system of records without their consent. The FCC is required to provide notice of its systems of records by publication in the Federal Register. The FCC published a systems of record notification (SORN) for the Lifeline Program that is designated as [FCC/WCB-1](https://transition.fcc.gov/omd/privacyact/documents/records/FCC-WCB-1.pdf). The National Lifeline Accountability Database (NLAD) and the Lifeline National Eligibility Verifier (National Verifier) are part of the FCC's Lifeline program systems of record (FCC/WCB-1) and the data is protected under the Privacy Act. USAC adheres to the Privacy Act requirements with respect to all information that it collects, maintains, uses, or disseminates in NLAD and the National Verifier.

If you participate in the Lifeline program, you will be asked to provide additional information to verify your eligibility to receive federal Lifeline benefits. This information includes first name, last name, address, last four digits of social security number (SSN) and date of birth. USAC will share this information that you provide with a third-party verification service to verify your identity and may share your data with other state and federal agencies to verify your eligibility to receive Lifeline support. In addition, your information may also be used for the purposes described in the SORN.

Show All
